http://www.usiouxfalls.edu/privacy-policy

×View USF's COVID-19 updates and resources.
Privacy Policy
This privacy policy applies to the website operated by the University of Sioux Falls referred to as "USF" herein.Website VisitorsExcept as described below, USF does not collect or require visitors to the website to furnish personally identifying information such as names, email addresses, and phone numbers. Like most website operators, USF does collect non-personally identifying information that web browsers and servers typically make available, such as the browser type, operating system, language preference, referring site and date and time of each visitor request. USF also collects potentially-personally identifying information like Internet Protocol (IP) addresses. These are non-personally identifying in and of themselves, but could be used in conjunction with other information to personally identify users.USF's purpose in collecting this information is to better understand how USF's visitors use its website. To that end, USF may share potentially-personally identifying information with its employees, contractors, service providers, and subsidiaries. USF will not publicly release potentially-personally identifying information except under the same circumstances as USF releases personally identifying information.Protection of Certain Personally-Identifying InformationWhere USF has collected personally identifying information, it discloses that information only to those of its employees, contractors, service providers, and subsidiaries that need to know that information in order to process it on USF's behalf and that have agreed not to disclose it to others. Additionally, USF may need to transfer personally identifying information to an affiliate or successor in the event of a change of our corporate structure or status, such as in the event of a restructuring, sale, or bankruptcy. We will retain any personally identifying information for the period necessary to fulfill the purposes outlined in this privacy policy. USF does not rent or sell personally identifying information to anyone.CookiesWhat Are Cookies? A cookie is a string of information that a website stores on a visitor's computer, and that the visitor's browser provides to the website each time the visitor returns. Most major websites use cookies. Because the browser provides this cookie information to the website at each visit, cookies serve as a sort of label that allows a website to "recognize" a browser when it returns to the site. The domain name in USF cookies will clearly identify their affiliation with USF and, where applicable, its third-party service provider.How We Use Cookies. USF's website uses cookies to help USF identify and track visitors, their usage of the USF website, and their website access preferences across multiple requests and visits to USF's website. The basic idea is to gather aggregate data about how people use the USF website. The term usually used to describe this is "web analytics" and the cookies are the tools by which a website owner collects this web analytics data.USF will use the web analytics data only to determine aggregate usage patterns for our website as described above. The USF website does this by using either our own internal analytics software or by sending this information to a third-party service provider to help USF analyze this data. USF has agreements with its third-party service providers that they will not share this information with others or use the information for purposes other than to maintain the services they provide to USF. It is possible to link cookies to personally identifying information, thereby permitting website operators, including our third-party analytics providers, to track the online movements of particular individuals. USF does not do so and its third-party service providers are not allowed to correlate USF data with any other data.USF uses the information provided by cookies to develop a better understanding of how USF's visitors use USF's website, and to facilitate those visitors' interactions with USF's website. USF may make the aggregate data obtained from web analytics (including from our third-party analytics providers, if applicable) publicly available. If this data is made available, none of the information will be personally identifying information or potentially-personally identifying information.How to Control the Use of Cookies. You have the ability to accept or decline cookies. USF visitors who do not wish to have cookies placed on their computers by USF, its contractors, or third-party service providers should set their browsers to refuse cookies before linking to USF's website. Certain features of USF's website may not function properly without the aid of cookies.Opt-out ProceduresIf you do not want data about your visits to the USF website to be collected by Google Analytics, you can install the Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on. The add-on keeps your visits anonymous and prohibits any data from being sent to Google Analytics. Additionally, if you signed up to receive but no longer wish to receive electronic marketing communications from USF, you can opt-out from receiving these communications by following the “unsubscribe” instructions in any such communication you receive.ChildrenUSF's website is not directed to individuals under the age of thirteen (13), and we request that such individuals do not provide personally identifying information through our website.Legal Process and Other DisclosuresConsistent with our privacy commitments, we will scrutinize third party requests for information about you for compliance with the law, including those coming from governmental agencies or civil litigants. We may access, use, preserve or disclose information about you only when we have a good faith belief that it is reasonably necessary to do so to satisfy the applicable law, regulation, legal process or lawful governmental request of any country, or to protect the rights, property or safety of USF, its users or the public. We will provide notice of legal process or governmental requests unless prohibited to do so by law or the circumstances warrant otherwise.Privacy Policy ChangesBy using the website, you agree to the terms and conditions of this privacy policy. If you do not agree to the terms and conditions of this privacy policy, please do not use the website. USF may change its Privacy Policy from time to time. Any and all changes will be reflected on this page
1101 W. 22nd St. Sioux Falls, SD 57105Contact Us(800) 888-1047Visit Campusvia Facebookvia Twittervia YouTubevia Instagramvia LinkedIn
Request Info
Apply Today
Visit Campus
Cost and Aid
AboutOpen About SectionHistoryAccreditations and MembershipsFast FactsLeadershipMission and VisionSioux Falls CommunityCampus MapCampus DirectoryAcademicsOpen Academics SectionUndergraduate Programs and MajorsGraduate ProgramsAdult LearnersOnline ProgramsLiberal ArtsVucurevich School of BusinessFredrikson School of EducationUSF School of NursingCenter for Professional DevelopmentLibraryBridges English Language ProgramAdmissionsOpen Admissions SectionHigh School StudentsGraduate StudentsTransfer and Adult StudentsInternational StudentsFinancial AidTuition and CostsUniversity ScholarshipsSchedule Your VisitCampus LifeOpen Campus Life SectionResidence HallsActivitiesCampus MinistriesService and Leadership OpportunitiesSupport ServicesVisit CampusCougar CentralThe ArtsOpen The Arts SectionArtMusicTheatreBuy TicketsAthleticsOpen Athletics SectionCalendarTicketsOfficesOpen Offices SectionOffice of the RegistrarFinancial AidStudent AccountsCampus Safety and SecurityCampus MailMy USFBack to top
×
